<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <title>ChineseAfterChineseSchool</title>
  <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io/</id>
  <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io/" />
  <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io//atom.xml" rel="self" />
  <updated>2015-01-22T17:01:40-08:00</updated>
  <rights>Copyright 2014, David Su</rights>
  <author>
    <name>David Su</name>
  </author>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Brick and Mortar Chinese for busy SF Bay Area Professionals</title>
      <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io//2015/01/13/brick-and-mortar-chinese-for-busy-sf-bay-area-professionals/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Before graduating college, I did a query for local private and public institutions to learn chinese that would be suitable for a 9-to-5er. Part of the reason why I’m self-studying for the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chinaeducenter.com/en/hsk/hsklevel5.php&quot;&gt;HSK 5&lt;/a&gt;, is because ultimately I wasn’t able to find a course for an advanced-intermediate chinese speaker seeking advanced proficiency. Nonetheless, I’m doing this writeup for busy working professionals who are not only considering courses and tutoring, but also activity based language groups such as toastmasters or meetups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;schools-and-tutors&quot;&gt;Schools and Tutors&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Firstly, most chinese language schools in the San Francisco Bay Area are listed on &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.wheretolearnchinese.com/component/jreviews/search-results/criteria:1/query:exact/jr_radius:5/jr_programsoffered:adult-education/order:rating.html&quot;&gt;wheretolearnchinese.com&lt;/a&gt;, but many of the leads for adult education are for Chinese cultural classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;community-colleges&quot;&gt;Community Colleges&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;California provides a listing of community colleges and you can filter it by &lt;a href=&quot;http://californiacommunitycolleges.cccco.edu/maps/map.asp?x=36&amp;amp;y=6&amp;amp;address=City%2C+Zip+or+Address&amp;amp;major=By+Academic+Program&amp;amp;area=Bay+Area&quot;&gt;community colleges in the Bay Area&lt;/a&gt; and also filter by &lt;a href=&quot;http://californiacommunitycolleges.cccco.edu/maps/map.asp?x=28&amp;amp;y=4&amp;amp;address=City%2C+Zip+or+Address&amp;amp;major=Chinese+%28Foreign+Language%29+&amp;amp;area=Bay+Area#&quot;&gt;academic programs&lt;/a&gt;. However, just go through the schools one by one in your area, and check for chinese programs on the school website since the data for Chinese academic programs in the community college database appears to be out of date. For example, San Jose City College courses are ommitted from the search results and Foothill’s defunct chinese program still appears in the results.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;universities&quot;&gt;Universities&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://youcango.collegeboard.org/college/locator/&quot;&gt;Generate a shortlist of colleges by zipcode&lt;/a&gt; and then find programs that offer open universities or have extension programs.
A shortlist includes &lt;a href=&quot;https://continuingstudies.stanford.edu/courses/courses-by-department&quot;&gt;Stanford&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://extension.berkeley.edu/public/category/programStream.do?method=load&amp;amp;selectedProgramAreaId=15497&amp;amp;selectedProgramStreamId=15595&quot;&gt;Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sjsu.edu/openuniversity/schedule/&quot;&gt;SJSU&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;tutors--others&quot;&gt;Tutors &amp;amp; Others&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;confucius-institute&quot;&gt;Confucius Institute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sfsu.edu/~ci/index.html&quot;&gt;Confucius Institute (孔子学院) at SFSU&lt;/a&gt; helps to administer HSK tests and also hosts classes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;defense-foreign-language-institute&quot;&gt;Defense Foreign Language Institute&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, I had a chance to compete in the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.cltac.org/speech-contest.html&quot;&gt;CLTAC Speech Competion (演講比賽)&lt;/a&gt;, and when looking at past results and competitors in the high school divisions I came across  the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.dliflc.edu/faqs.html&quot;&gt;Defense Foreign Language Institute&lt;/a&gt;, which only offers courses to members of the armed forces.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;craigslist&quot;&gt;Craigslist&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Besides buying house furniture, who knew &lt;a href=&quot;http://sfbay.craigslist.org/search/lss?query=mandarin&quot;&gt;tutors advertised on craigslist?&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;yelp&quot;&gt;Yelp&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I tried “chinese language school” and “chinese tutor” as my search terms.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If your searching by cities, it’s impossible to find locations &amp;gt; 5 mile radius from your target city. My workaround was to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/search?find_desc=mandarin+tutor&amp;amp;find_loc=San+Francisco%2C+CA#find_loc=San+Francisco+Bay+Area,+CA&quot;&gt;search by larger geographic regions&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some interesting results produced included the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/dennis-language-services-san-francisco&quot;&gt;man who voices Rosetta stone lessons&lt;/a&gt;, a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/california-chinese-culture-learning-studio-san-francisco-2?hrid=XGVFF4A0_Y71qOTrPDOumg&quot;&gt;learning studio ran by a mom&lt;/a&gt;, and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/kaixin-language-school-san-francisco-2?hrid=dWeC38bZGt-hJX6g2jTCVQ&quot;&gt;a Spanish and Chinese school with a sleek website&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;wyzant&quot;&gt;Wyzant&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;While running google queries for tutors, I kept on coming across &lt;a href=&quot;http://wyzant.com&quot;&gt;wyzant.com&lt;/a&gt;. Rates tend to hover around $50/hr with the highest I encountered at $90/hr. If you are wary about wyzant as a company, you can read this &lt;a href=&quot;http://techcrunch.com/2013/12/16/wyzant-lands-21-5m-from-accel-to-take-its-tutoring-marketplace-global-and-mobile/&quot;&gt;TechCrunch report about the company&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;language-meetups&quot;&gt;Language Meetups&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think find a group via &lt;a href=&quot;http://chinese-language.meetup.com/&quot;&gt;Chinese language Meetup Groups&lt;/a&gt; will put me in contact with local language enthusiasts and afford for me a chance to put practice into effect in an immersive environment. Understandably skill levels vary greatly, some organizers might also have additional motives to promote their language schools, but I can afford to take a breather and go out to meet people.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;toastmasters&quot;&gt;Toastmasters&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have some enjoyed my past experience in toastmasters practicing public speaking and in the SF Bay Area and there are Mandarin-English toastmasters located in &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/SF-MET/&quot;&gt;San Francisco&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.meetup.com/MET-clubs/&quot;&gt;Milpitas&lt;/a&gt;. Toastmasters usually start off giving speeches at 4 minutes and work their way up to longer times. There are also opportunities to talk for 1-2 minutes during table topic discussions. I don’t expect people to be correcting my grammar for speeches since speeches are usually roughly outlined before delivery and not fully written out, but I do hope to improve my chinese listening ability by recording native-Chinese speeches and listening to them until I comprehend them. I can also have a member record me and analyze where I can add more content to my speech.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;bookstores&quot;&gt;Bookstores&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you’re looking for books hot off the Chinese press, you may be surprised that there is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ozy.com/good-sht/the-most-popular-books-in-china-and-why/32503&quot;&gt;budding online reading culture in China&lt;/a&gt;. Combo the html-based book with a &lt;a href=&quot;https://chrome.google.com/webstore/detail/zhongwen-a-chinese-englis/kkmlkkjojmombglmlpbpapmhcaljjkde?hl=en&quot;&gt;pop-up dictionary&lt;/a&gt; and an audiobook (有聲讀物) from &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.ximalaya.com/&quot;&gt;ximalaya&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kting.cn/&quot;&gt;kting.cn&lt;/a&gt;, or &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yousheng8.com/&quot;&gt;yousheng8&lt;/a&gt; and you may be in for reading nirvana. I have yet to complete a book with this method, but it appears promising. An italki friend recommended to me books written by &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.kanunu8.com/files/writer/189.html&quot;&gt;Giddens Ko&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nonetheless, with the proliferation of online bookstores and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.latimes.com/local/great-reads/la-me-c1-chinese-bookstores-20141125-story.html&quot;&gt;hard-times for chinese bookstores&lt;/a&gt;, it’s sometimes refreshing to get my hands on a physical copy of the book before making a purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ve only personally made a trip to &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/eastwind-books-of-berkeley-berkeley-2&quot;&gt;Eastwind Books of Berkeley&lt;/a&gt; which has &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.asiabookcenter.com/textbooks.html&quot;&gt;partnerships with UC Berkeley&lt;/a&gt;, and though their collection for bilingual books is small (I could only find Pride and Prejudice), what struck me was their collection of books pertaining to Asian American studies, a topic I haven’t really read into but it may be worth reading for leisure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On my to-do list is to visit:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/china-books-south-san-francisco&quot;&gt;Chinabooks&lt;/a&gt;: Has a large collection of books including the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chinabooks.com/product-category/chinese-text3/k8textbooks/new-practical-chinese-reader-series/&quot;&gt;New Practical Chinese Reader Series&lt;/a&gt;, which I came across on the web.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/eastwind-books-and-arts-san-francisco-3&quot;&gt;Eastwind Books - unrelated to Berkeley Eastwind&lt;/a&gt;: Has a collection of traditional chinese books in addition to simplified chinese. Also, some of the books may appeal to the young adult.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Some other mentions:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/soyodo-millbrae&quot;&gt;Soyodo&lt;/a&gt;: There appears to a few stores in California named Soyodo, though they don’t appear to have any relation to each other. This store also does double duty as a computer repair store.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.yelp.com/biz/nan-hai-bookstore-santa-clara&quot;&gt;Nanhai Books&lt;/a&gt;: Apparently the same address also belongs to the &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.chinaeducenter.com/en/hsk/hsktestcenter_pacific.php&quot;&gt;Hanban Chinese Online Testing Center&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;calculations&quot;&gt;Calculations&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So as a 9-to-5-er I’ll probably have about 3-4 hours of expendable time each weekday. In actuality, my timeline will look more like 8am to 8:00pm since I anticipate work to end at 6-7pm, and adding about an 1 hour of padding on either side of the timeframe for commute.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Therefore, I’m looking for either nightly classes or weekend classes. Although &lt;a href=&quot;http://kaixinlanguageschool.com/programs/kaixin-mandarin/&quot;&gt;Kaixin School&lt;/a&gt; does have some weekend classes and I was able to find nightly classes at &lt;a href=&quot;http://www3.dvc.edu/org/info/schedules/course-detail.htm?keySection=8082Spring2015Chinese&quot;&gt;Diablo Valley College&lt;/a&gt;, both of them appear to be out of my current scope for advanced-intermediate chinese learners. Coupled with the 30min+ commute from the South Bay, I have extra disincentive to take these courses.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest realization of as an ex-student, is that you soon realize that &lt;strong&gt;a large portion of learning comes from self-studying&lt;/strong&gt; and finding help by way of professors, TAs (Teaching Assistants), or other peers. I’m also not expecting taking a class to render my a fluent mandarin speaker, otherwise, I wouldn’t still be blogging here today in spite of receiving mandarin education since I could remember.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I do plan on trying out a toastmaster, a meetup, and plan to take the HSK in March 2015 before considering to get a tutor if I don’t pass.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Should I consider paying for a class, I will ask for a diagnostic test, a trial lesson, sample coursework, class expectations, and a referral that I could talk to before I consider spending.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;conclusion&quot;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My ultimate conclusion after doing a survey of brick and mortar chinese language schools, is that &lt;strong&gt;in the San Francisco Bay Area there are no mandarin courses for the advanced-intermediate chinese learner and working professional&lt;/strong&gt; (In my terms, an advanced-intermediate is equivalent to HSK 4 aptitude and completion of 3rd year university classes). As a 9-to-5er, I am left with the choice to either self-study or call it quits and go back to schooling.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since all this is but a hobby, I’m choosing  to take the self-study route! Stay tuned for monthly language goals and my current learning methodologies!&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io//2015/01/13/brick-and-mortar-chinese-for-busy-sf-bay-area-professionals/</id>
      <updated>2015-01-13T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>David Su</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>Impressions of Italki</title>
      <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io//2014/12/22/italki-first-impressions/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;When I started this post-grad journey of learning mandarin, my brother told me that one of his friends started using &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com&quot;&gt;italki&lt;/a&gt; to schedule online classes with teachers.
After a month and a half of using italki, I wanted to share with you my impressions. I haven’t payed for any lessons yet, but have read a couple of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/articles&quot;&gt;teachers articles&lt;/a&gt;,  written some &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/user/1701796#notebook&quot;&gt;notebook entries&lt;/a&gt;, and had 2 language exchange conversations and counting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;italki-incentives&quot;&gt;Italki Incentives&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/giftcards?utm_source=dashboardad&amp;amp;utm_medium=website&amp;amp;utm_campaign=holidayseason2014&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/italki-gift-card.png&quot; alt=&quot;Italki Gift Card&quot; /&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Italki has created some incentives such as their gift cards, recent &lt;a href=&quot;http://promos.italki.com/italki-2014-october-language-challenge/&quot;&gt;language challenge&lt;/a&gt;, referral credits, and non-redeemable italki points. I’ll briefly discuss about their credit and italki points, but I personally believe that the most attractive feature of the website is the language exchange network.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;italki-points&quot;&gt;Italki Points&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;italki-points-ne-itc-italki-credits&quot;&gt;Italki Points ≠ ITC (ITalki Credits)&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/italki-points.png&quot; alt=&quot;Italki Points&quot; /&gt;
The first day I found italki, I was ecstatic that every notebook correction I made increased my italki points and I was expecting to reap the full benefits of the site (such as credit toward lessons) without paying. Wow, I thought to myself now that I have 500 or so Italki points within 2 days, how many lessons I can have? Upon further inspection and much to my dismay, I realized that &lt;a href=&quot;http://support.italki.com/entries/21629711-italki-Points-What-are-they-&quot;&gt;italki points&lt;/a&gt; have been an experimental feature for over 2 years and counting and my way to cope with this disappointment was to view the points as reputation points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;italki-points--reputation-points&quot;&gt;Italki Points = “Reputation Points”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I believe that italki points are good insofar as identifying long-term members. Among some of the most prolific users among mandarin learners is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/user/718609&quot;&gt;Jeff&lt;/a&gt;, and if I ever get a chance I would be more than curious on what gets him to contribute to the community on a consistent basis. I’m also curious italki points will be utilized in the future, but right now it’s just a cosmetic ego booster.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;a-big-win-language-exchange&quot;&gt;A Big Win: Language Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Virtual credits aside, what brings me back to the site is the language exchange network. I can find people who are also invested in learning languages!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;notable-features&quot;&gt;Notable Features&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;lessons-yet-to-try&quot;&gt;Lessons: Yet to Try&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Quite frankly, I haven’t tried this out yet, since I’m adamant about self-studying awhile for the HSK 5. I plan on &lt;a href=&quot;http://sarajaaksola.com/preparing-for-the-new-hsk-level-5-exam/&quot;&gt;buying a mock test book&lt;/a&gt; mentioned by a successful test taker and perusing the other &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.fluentu.com/chinese/blog/2014/10/27/resources-prepare-mandarin-chinese-new-hsk-exam/&quot;&gt;HSK resources mentioned by FluentU&lt;/a&gt;. I do, however, appreciate that there are competitively priced trial lessons, and that the certified teachers do post their video introductions on to the page, so you can get a taste for their teaching style. After making your first purchase of ITC credits, you do get a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/premium&quot;&gt;premium badge&lt;/a&gt; on your profile, which seems to give your questions more prominence and notebook entries more prominence. By guesstimation, most of the pricing for chinese tutors are around $15 per hour of class. In college, we usually had 4 hours of discussion a week in addition to maybe 4 to 5 hours of homework a week, which could cost around $60 dollars a week.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;notebook&quot;&gt;Notebook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I think this is a great idea for people to actually practice writing, but since I started using italki, I found another service called &lt;a href=&quot;lang-8&quot;&gt;lang-8.com&lt;/a&gt; which is primarily focused on writing. My initial posts was a translation for newspaper ad about a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/entry/486319&quot;&gt;Tea station&lt;/a&gt; and a news article Forbes magazine article about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/entry/486835&quot;&gt;job hunting for new grads&lt;/a&gt;. I’ve gotten quality corrections both on italki and lang-8, except I have a strong hunch that longer writings (especially essays) are more suited for the lang-8 community. For example in my most recent post on my recent language learning methods, I received &lt;a href=&quot;http://lang-8.com/1091561/journals/256231660350717783193269096223025204986&quot;&gt;3 revisions within the first 24 hours on lang-8&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/entry/499046&quot;&gt;1 revision within the first hour on italki&lt;/a&gt;. For now, I’m cross-posting on both platforms. On italki, it’s also interesting to see what people have posted as a way to see how other people your level write, and I was particularly intrigued by an opinion piece about &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.italki.com/entry/499122&quot;&gt;artificial intelligence （人工智能）&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;language-exchange&quot;&gt;Language Exchange&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/italki-language-exchange-search.png&quot; alt=&quot;Language Exchange search&quot; /&gt;
This is the feature that I find the most exciting! The format I’ve been using so far is 1 hour language exchange with 1/2 english and 1/2 mandarin over skype.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;speaking-with-natives-gets-me-excited-about-language-learning&quot;&gt;Speaking with Natives gets me excited about Language Learning&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It’s very validating to be able to speak with a native speaker, because your language skills are put to the test. It’s great because you don’t have to worry about holding back and revising as you do when writing an essay or blog post, but rather the focus is to just generate a lot of speech, identity words that you wish you could say, and words that your partner says as well. Also, since the exchange is mutual beneficial, it’s rewarding to know that someone else is benefiting from the exchange.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;finding-language-partners-is-a-numbers-game-follow-up&quot;&gt;Finding Language Partners is a Numbers Game. Follow up!&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My goal right now is to get 2 to 4 language partners of both Taiwanese Chinese and Mainland Chinese background so that I can get accustomed to the ways that both accents of mandarin are spoken.
So far I’ve reached out to or have been contacted by 14 different potential language exchange partners or another. Some are either no longer active users or just gave me a virtual cold shoulder (I can’t tell the difference!), for others there may have been some initial interest but we hadn’t successful setup a meetup so nothing came to fruition.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;coordinating-timezones&quot;&gt;Coordinating Timezones&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To accommodate a 9-6pm workday, I’ve proposed the following timeframes to propsective partners:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7am-8am PST / 11pm - 12am CST and Taiwan Time (Haven’t had any sessions at this time yet)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10pm-12am PST / 2pm - 4pm CST and Taiwan Time (Had 2 sessions and counting)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m very thankful that I’ve been able to find times at the 10pm PST timezone.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;the-first-talk&quot;&gt;The First Talk&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I envisioned this to be pretty much like the 30 minute coffee that that many seekers probably have over the phone with recruiters, where you are trying to learn more about the persons background.
When I’m on the speaking side, I just try to generate different aspects about my life (why I learned chinese, my experience in Boy Scouts, etc). In my first two language exchanges, the person speaking the non-native language will probably spend most of the time talking. I want to get the conversation to the point where both partners are interacting fairly equally in the conversation, so that when the native-speaking partner is speaking, the non-native can practice listening comprehension.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;keep-it-casual&quot;&gt;Keep it Casual&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Are you enjoying yourself?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;ask-a-lot-of-questions&quot;&gt;Ask a lot of questions&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Especially for speaking, I like to ask, how do you say “x”? Sometimes, when I can’t find the words to speak the sentence, I try to say what I want to say in broken chinese, then fluent english, and then my partner translates what I meant to say in Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;try-not-to-make-corrections-unless-prompted&quot;&gt;Try not to make corrections unless prompted&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I do this as a means of not interrupting the flow, and if I don’t quite understand what they are saying I try to rephrase what they say, upgrading vocabulary words from the original sentence if appropriate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;language-exchange-todos&quot;&gt;Language Exchange Todos&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;finding-topics-to-talk-about-after-session-1&quot;&gt;Finding Topics to talk about after session 1&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This will be interesting to see what types of topics, I will be talking with about with my language exchange partners after the first exchange and months down the road.  A quick google for “Language exchange topics” will probably produce quite a few results as well as this list of &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.tobefluent.com/2014/09/02/language-exchange-so-what-do-you-want-to-talk-about/&quot;&gt;32 topics&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;recording-calls&quot;&gt;Recording Calls&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;With permission, I think it will be very cool to record the calls and see the results of our language exchange after a few months. Furthermore, audio recordings will allow me to review some of the topics we talked about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;precautions&quot;&gt;Precautions&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;rd-party-accounts-are-publicly-visible&quot;&gt;3rd-party Accounts are publicly visible&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first I linked my facebook account, so I would only have one less password to memorize, but after I found out that my profile is linked on the italki page, I unlinked my account just as a precautionary measure for privacy.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;summary&quot;&gt;Summary&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Italki provides some incentives to save you a dollar such as their referral program, gift card deals, and language challenges.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Among their features, my favorite is the Language Exchange network!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m curious how you have tailored your italki lessons (for HSK, Business Chinese, etc) and if you have any great stories about your language exchange experience.&lt;/p&gt;
</summary>
      <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io//2014/12/22/italki-first-impressions/</id>
      <updated>2014-12-22T00:00:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>David Su</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
    <entry>
      <title>A Rallying Cry for ChineseAfterChineseSchool</title>
      <link href="http://davidtingsu.github.io//2014/12/01/rallying-cry-for-chineseafterchineseschool/" />
      <summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;Hello world! 歡迎光臨！ I am an American Born Chinese (ABC) millennial seeking to bolster my mandarin levels from a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ILR_scale#ILR_Level_2_.E2.80.93_Limited_working_proficiency&quot;&gt;limited working proficiency&lt;/a&gt; to that of a  &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ILR_scale#ILR_Level_3_.E2.80.93_Professional_working_proficiency&quot;&gt;professional working proficiency&lt;/a&gt; or &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/ILR_scale#ILR_Level_5_.E2.80.93_Native_or_bilingual_proficiency&quot;&gt;native proficiency&lt;/a&gt;. This blog will document my adventures and misadventures of learning Mandarin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I write with the perspective of a Chinese American who grew up in a &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=chinglish&quot;&gt;chinglish&lt;/a&gt; speaking household, who has received mandarin schooling since childhood until university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;k-8&quot;&gt;K-8&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My education in American from K-8 school consisted of attending weekly chinese schools. I learned the mandarin ABCs/BoPoMoFo/注音符號/zhùyīnfúhào in my Saturday preschool and kindergarten class, and spent my Friday evenings from 7pm to 9pm writing hanzi from 1st grade all the way to the end of first semester 8th grade.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fundamentally &lt;b&gt;learning mandarin was a chore for most of the formative years of my life&lt;/b&gt;. There were countless days where my mom would be rushing down to the final hour to help my brothers and myself finish our chinese homework packet. Afterwards, we would wolf down our dinners, scurry into class, get grilled with a written memorization test, spend another hour reviewing and engaging in new course material, before heading home with the relief of being done. Next week, I would rinse and repeat again! Chinese school was by far one of the most stressful days of my K-8 education. Digging up my old chinese schoolwork, I realized that some of the texts we were reading were comparable to university level grammar, but &lt;b&gt;I survived chinese school using my parents as a walking dictionary&lt;/b&gt;. Take a look at some of the homework packets circa 2001 and 2005!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;high-school&quot;&gt;High School&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In high school, Chinese was offered as a language class and I was able to start out an intermediate level with many fellow chinese school classmates. This marked a greater emphasis on typing essays using hanyu pinyin instead of writing them out on specialized stationary paper. This also marked the first time in my mandarin education history, where I had a lesser dependence on looking up words by radical stroke and would often blindy use google translate to translate a word. I remember initially having a particular mindset about how chinese should be taught and even told my teacher that should do more drilling since I thought the class was not rigorous enough.   Later on in high school, I sought out chinese as one of the easier classes since one could buffer their own grades with extra credit points. One rowdy student went so far as to inscribe “加分” (add points) into the classroom ceiling wall. I really remember high school chinese as a  fun-loving class, interspersed with a seemingly never-ending number of poster presentations and cultural events, and over-inflated test scores. Please feel free to peruse some of works during my high school years &lt;a href=&quot;http://davidsu.weebly.com/&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;college&quot;&gt;College&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In college, it wasn’t until senior year, that I took up chinese again. So what exactly was the impetus for this? I had always talked the talk about enrolling in university chinese, but it wasn’t until senior year until I felt a spur to take my last set of classes before graduation. In approaching my senior year of college, I felt a great sense of urgency to take some of the non-major classes I had always wanted to take or were recommended to me such as chinese, personal finance, and product management. Yes, these are the symptoms of graduation fever: making the best of your last year at school! I wanted to get exposure to the university level (3rd year chinese) chinese, because I wanted to improve leaps and bounds with the vast resources available under my nose. The university experience was reminiscent of my high school days in that the small classroom structure of about 20 to 30 people is conducive to personable interaction with teachers and classmates, something that I craved in stark contrast to the large lecture groups that I had become accustomed. But I digress. Fundamentally, the ultimate reason to take chinese was because &lt;strong&gt;I take pride in my cultural identity&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&quot;why&quot;&gt;Why?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So why I am I writing this blog? Towards the ends of graduation I was heedful of the old time quip  “Use it or lose it”, which can suffice to explain itself. Not wanting my mandarin skills to deteriorate, I perused the web for evening or weekend college courses, meetups, and online resources to pursue and experiment. I’m hoping to appeal to 2nd-generation overseas chinese, Nth-generation overseas chinese, intermediate mandarin learners, 1st generation overseas Chinese Americans about the struggles of “2nd-gens” learning mandarin, &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.urbandictionary.com/define.php?term=laowai&quot;&gt;lǎowài&lt;/a&gt;老外, and general language enthusiasts. I’m writing to many John and Jane Does who are interested in crafting their mandarin education as they see it, whether as a hobby or a marketable skill.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Stay tuned as I write about my daily study routine, studying processes, chinese education financials, attempting the &lt;a href=&quot;http://english.hanban.org/node_8002.htm&quot;&gt;HSK&lt;/a&gt;, attempting &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sc-top.org.tw/english/eng_index.php&quot;&gt;TOP&lt;/a&gt;, book reviews, and creating an immersive environment among many others. Don’t hesitate to help me ideate!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;additional-motivation&quot;&gt;Additional Motivation&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of my former Chinese teachers told me about how she came to the states as a young adult with virtually no knowledge of the English in a foreign land of opportunity. She told me about how she first pursued her ESL education scouring the net to expand her vocabulary and later built her oral skills listening to English podcasts. Years later, she earned a college degree in the U.S. and continued her passion for teaching Chinese. Even as a teacher, she continued to expand her knowledge of the English language which was nonetheless impressive for someone who acquired English as a language in her adulthood. When asked how I can attain a higher level of fluency, she told me to continue practicing. I share with her a strong desire to continue and want to share this with you guys.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Charge on. Fighting. 加油！&lt;/p&gt;

</summary>
      <id>http://davidtingsu.github.io//2014/12/01/rallying-cry-for-chineseafterchineseschool/</id>
      <updated>2014-12-01T01:49:00-08:00</updated>
      <author>
        <name>David Su</name>
      </author>
    </entry>
  
</feed>
